# **Garland Key**

**Full Stack Software Engineer** 

# **Summary**

I'm a full stack software engineer with decades of experience working solo and in teams to solve critical problems with innovative solutions. The personal strengths I bring to a team are my creative and analytical skills, my desire to help others, and my positive, eager attitude. As a generalist, I excel at learning how things work and adapting to new challenges. My strong work ethic drives me to deliver excellence in everything I do, both in my professional and personal life. I want to produce work I can take pride in.

# **Work Experience**

## Full Stack Software Engineer at 100Devs, Los Angeles, CA

October 2020 - Present

- Collaborated with a team of developers to build modern and responsive web applications.
- Built semantically structured full stack web applications.
- Applied agile methodologies like SCRUM while on the project management team.

## **Contract Web Developer**

January 2000 – October 2020

**IMPACT Center for Independent Living** – During covid, it was almost impossible for people with disabilities to make it into IMPACT's office to fill out the necessary forms for receiving aid. Their website was out of date and had several noticeable bugs. I created a full-stack application for this non-profit organization that provides crucial information to consumers, allows consumers to complete government aid forms from within the website, and provides an avenue for people in the community to donate. As a result, donations have risen and the application process for consumers has become far more accessible.

#### ERS II at AAA, St. Louis, MO

October 2017 – September 2021

- Provided a supervisory role and assisted with the training of over 30 new employees.
- Assisted an average of 100 members a day with critical emergency roadside issues.
- Correspond with local emergency services to keep thousands of members safe in dangerous roadside situations.

## **Recent Projects**

thinkBig - code 2

An educational web application that facilitates long-distance learning.

DSTOR - code <a>™</a>

A community-driven, free and open source, peer-reviewed journal storage system.

Darling & Mason – code <a>I</a> website <a>I</a></a>

A beautiful, responsible, visually accessible premier salon website.

# **Volunteer Experience**

#### **Progressive Coders** - 2022

I've contributed code to a number of projects maintained by the non-profit organization. I also help educate volunteers on the basics of full stack web development.

#### Skills

#### **Frontend**

- CSS
- HTML
- JavaScript
- Next.js
- Object-oriented Programming
- React.js

#### **Backend**

- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- Node.is
- PostareSOL
- Prisma

## Project Management

- Agile
- Scrum
- Team Leadership

#### Misc

- Bash
- C
- Git
- Github
- Linux
- NPM
- NVM

## Design

- Figma
- Illustrator
- Inkscape
- Krita
- Lightroom Classic
- Photoshop

#### Education

## Parkland College 2004

Anthropology